American Association of University Women, Albany Chapter; Records apap002
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Annual Reports, 1940-1965; 4; 0.5 cubic ft.
  - Annual Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 10)
  - Annual Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 11)
  - Annual Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 12)
  - Annual Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (4-Annual Reports), Folder 13)
- Committee Files, 1937-1990; 5; 0.67 cubic ft.
  These files document the work performed by individual committees and their respective chairmen. The series is broken down into seven subseries, each corresponding to a particular committee: Branch History Committee, Fellowship Committee, Hospitality Committee, Membership Committee, Program Committee, Public Information Committee, and the Antique Study Group. Documents within the Committee Files folders are filed chronologically excepting the chairmen's correspondence files, which are filed in reverse chronological order.
  - Antique Study Group Chairman's File, 1959-1975 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 1)
  - Branch History Committee Chairman's File, 1937-1990 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 2)
  - Branch History Committee - History Material, 1938-1965; 1989/1990 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 3)
  - Branch History Committee - Events, 1937-1938 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 4)
  - Fellowships Committee Chairman's File, 1955-1960 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 5)
  - Fellowships Committee Chairman's File, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 6)
  - Fellowships Committee Chairman's File, 1963-1964 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 7)
  - Fellowships Committee Chairman's Correspondence (1 of 2), 1939-1940 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 8)
  - Fellowships Committee Chairman's Correspondence (2 of 2), 1939-1940 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 1)
  - Fellowships Committee Chairman's Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 2)
  - Hospitality Committee Chairman's File, 1954-1969 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 3)
  - Membership Committee Chairman's File, 1979-1990 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 4)
  - Membership Committee Membership Surveys, 1961-1962 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 5)
  - Program Committee Chairman's File, 1942-1989 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 6)
  - Program Committee Program Schedules, 1984-1989 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 7)
  - Public Information Committee Press Releases, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 8)
  - Public Information Committee Pamphlets, 1969 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 9)
  - Public Information Committee Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 2 (5-Committee Files), Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1936-1965; 6; 1.0 cubic ft.
  Arranged chrnologically.
  The Correspondence files are separated into three subseries: Correspondence with Community Organizations, 1941-1953; Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State and Division, 1951-1957; and General Correspondence, 1936-1965. Documents within the folders are filed in reverse chronological order. The only gaps in the series occur in the General Correspondence files: 1944-1946 and 1951-1952.
  - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1941-1953; 6.1
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1941-1942 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1942-1943 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1943-1944 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1944-1945 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1945-1946 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1946-1947 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1947-1948 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1949-1950 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1950 -1951 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1951-1952 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Community Service Organizations, 1952-1953 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State Division, 1951-1957; 6.2
    - Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State Division, 1951-1953 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State Division, 1953-1954 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State Division, 1954-1955 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State Division, 1955-1956 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with AAUW Headquarters and New York State Division, 1956-1957 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (General), 1936-1965; 6.3
    - Correspondence (General), 1936-1943 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (General), 1947-1950 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (General), 1953-1954 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Correspondence (General), 1954-1955 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Correspondence (General), 1955-1956 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Correspondence (General) (1 of 2), 1956-1957 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Correspondence (General) (2 of 2), 1956-1957 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Correspondence (General), 1958-1959 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Correspondence (General), 1959-1960 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Correspondence (General), 1960-1961 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Correspondence (General), 1961-1962 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Correspondence (General), 1962-1964 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Correspondence (General) (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Correspondence (General) (2 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Correspondence (General), 1964-1965 (Box 1 (6-Correspondence), Folder 31)
- Bulletins, 1941-1990; 7; 0.5 cubic ft.
  The AAUW Albany Branch Bulletins are distributed monthly to inform members of meeting dates and locations, changing policies, current positions on legislative issues, upcoming events, and dues information. The bulletins contain no gaps.
  - Bulletins, 1941-1946 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1947-1951 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1952-1954 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1955-1958 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1959-1965 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1966-1971 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1972-1975 (Box 1 (7-Bulletins), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1976-1981 (Box 2 (7-Bulletins), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (7-Bulletins), Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1985-1990 (Box 2 (7-Bulletins), Folder 3)
- Yearbooks, 1913-1991; 8; 0.34 cubic ft.
  arranged chronologically.
  The Albany Branch Yearbooks contain the names, telephone numbers, and addresses of all members of the branch. The yearbooks are text only, there are no photos. The yearbooks contain no gaps.
  - Yearbooks, 1913-1940 (Box 1 (8-Yearbooks), Folder 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1940-1960 (Box 1 (8-Yearbooks), Folder 2)
  - Yearbooks, 1960-1980 (Box 1 (8-Yearbooks), Folder 3)
  - Yearbooks, 1980-1990 (Box 1 (8-Yearbooks), Folder 4)
- Scrapbooks and Ephemera, 1936-1972; 9; 1.0 cubic ft.
  This series contains scrapbooks of newspaper clippings and documentary material of the Albany branch's activities, members, and interests. Other ephemeral items contained in the series include photographs, proclamations of the Mayor of Albany, clothing and tote bags.
  - AAUW T-shirt, yellow, Undated (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - AAUW tote bag, white, Undated (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - AAUW tote bag, red, Undated (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - ERA apron, blue, Undated (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Christmas song book, Undated (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Career Fair photographs, 1981 (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Proclamations, City of Albany New York, Office of the Mayor, 1989; 1991 (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Scrapbook #1, Publicity Notes, 1941-1957 (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Scrapbook #2, Publicity, public information, 1963-1972 (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Scrapbook #3, 1950-1962 (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))
  - Scrapbook #4, 1936-1941 (Box 1 (9-Scrapbooks and Ephemera))